James Mulligan

LITTLE EGG HARBOR, NJ 08087 | (609) 618-5719 | 87JMulligan@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-mulligan

Portfolio: https://jmulligan87.github.io/ | GitHub: https://github.com/JMulligan87

Summary

Flexibility. Creativity. Collaboration. Attention to detail. Full stack web developer with knowledge in several front-end and back-end languages, responsive frameworks, databases and best code practices. Currently transitioning into a web development career with extensive experience in customer service. Self motivated and adept at working with diverse teams to implement projects. Experience with troubleshooting along with a desire to learn new things.

Technical Skills

Front-End: React, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS
Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, Axios, Mongoose, Sequelize

• Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

• SoftWare: Visual Studio Code, MySQL Workbench, Robo3T, Postman

Tools: Git/Github, NPM, Heroku, FirebaseOperating Systems: Windows, MacOS

Projects

Aman Imman Field App

Github: https://github.com/JMulligan87/field-app

Deployed: https://immanfieldapp.herokuapp.com

Team Facilitator:

Amman Imman is a non-profit NGO that works in the Azawak region of Africa, in between Niger and Mali. This was a collaborative project that allows local field nurses and team members to train individuals on multiple health and sanitation practices that otherwise would not have been available to them. We used visual representations as a universal communicator.

• Front-End: React, JavaScript, CSS and Bootstrap • Databases: MongoDB, Mongoose • Back End: Node.js, Express.js • Project Management: Git, Git Bash • Deployment: Heroku

Meal Maker

Github: https://github.com/JMulligan87/MealMaker

Deployed: https://mealmakerpro.herokuapp.com

Team Facilitator:

Meal Maker is a full stack project where users can search recipes entered by other users and can also add their own recipes to the database.

• Front-End: HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS and Bootstrap • Databases: MySQL, Sequelize • Back End: Node.js, Express.js • Project Management: Git, Git Bash • Deployment: Heroku

Experience

MAY 2010 - PRESENT

The Chicken or the Egg, Beach Haven, NJ - Server

- Consistently achieved the highest guest check averages among all full-time servers through suggestive selling and time management.
- Informally recognized as Lead Server with responsibility for overseeing opening / closing and coaching and mentoring new servers regarding menu items, company policies and procedures.
- Frequently assisted colleagues during rush periods to foster / promote teamwork while providing exceptional service and guest dining experience.

2005 - 2010

Men at Work Landscaping, Mayetta, NJ - Contractor

- Completed jobs within a set deadline.
- Made executive decisions when the foreman was not on site.

Education

MAY 2019 - NOVEMBER 2019

Rutgers University, Somerset - Coding Bootcamp

Fast-paced program focused on fundamentals of front- and back-end web development, real-world problem solving, and collaboration.